# STEPHEN TOTTEN

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

# CONTACT 682-365-8731 s.g.totten@gmail.com https://github.com/Crothos Fort Worth, Texas SKILLS HTML5 CSS JavaScript React Node.js Express Git & GitHub Agile Development SQL Databases Mongo DB (NOSQL) Heroku MVC & 00P EDUCATION **Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certification UT Austin School for**

# Professional Education

2022-2023

Full Stack (MERN) Web Developer Certification

Bachelor's of Arts

#### **University of North Texas**

2003-2006

Radio/TV/Film

#### PROFILE

Recent Full Stack Bootcamp graduate with 14 years experience working remotely for a non-profit providing high-quality closed captions for live television. Fell in love with coding during school and acted as project manager for three different successfully launched web apps.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Live Voice Writer**

National Captioning Institute

2008-2022

- Provided closed captions for primarily live television in real time using voice recognition software and IP connection software.
- Successfully worked remotely for over 12 years self-motivating and selfassessing.
- Provided captions with an average of over 98% accuracy rate.
- Was the only voice captioner skilled enough to provide captions for G4, the former gaming and tech channel.

#### **Live Streamer & Podcaster**

2012-Current

Self-Employed

- Designed and executed weekly video stream content on Twitch.tv, maintaining a production schedule for over 10 years.
- Utilized social media and Discord server to maintain community engagement.
- Edited and published weekly video content on YouTube, Tiktok, and other social media outlets.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

- Graphic design and promotional marketing to drive live event attendance.
- Built a steady monthly income stream from scratch.
- Grew average viewership over 400% over 5 years.

# PROJECTS

## **Learn With Flash!**

- Front-end application that allows users to utilize both created and custom flashcards to facilitate learning for all ages.
- Deployed URL: https://crothos.github.io/flashcard-app/
- Repo URL: https://github.com/Crothos/flashcard-app/

#### **Budget Buddy**

- Full-stack application using a SQL database to help users track expenses.
- Deployed URL: https://financial-planner-uta-bc.herokuapp.com/
- Repo URL: https://github.com/Crothos/financial-planner/

#### **Git Your Life Together**

- Full stack application using a NOSQL/MongoDB database that allows users to create and track projects, breaking them down into completable steps, integrating ChatGPT.
- Deployed URL: https://git-your-life-together.herokuapp.com/
- Repo URL: https://github.com/JessicalOrtega/Glt-your-life-together-/